When Śrīla Guru Mahārāj was asked some questions,
Quando a Śrīla Guru Mahārāj furono fatte delle domande,
actually by the ISKCON artists who were preparing
in realtà da artisti della ISKCON che si stavano preparando
[The Devil is in the Details]
[Il Diavolo è Nei Dettagli]
to create paintings for the Brahma Saṁhitā,
a creare pitture per la Brahma Saṁhitā.
I brought them there and introduced them to Guru Mahārāj
Li condussi lì e li presentai a Guru Mahārāj
and they had some questions to ask.
e loro avevano delle domande da fare.
And there are some mystical descriptions
Ci sono delle descrizioni mistiche
in the beginning of the Brahma Saṁhitā,
all'inizio della Brahma Saṁhitā,
and they started asking Śrīla Guru Mahārāj about this
ed a tal proposito, cominciarono a fare domande a Śrīla Guru Mahārāj
so that they would know how to paint,
così da sapere come dipingere
and Guru Mahārāj said, “I’m sorry,
e Guru Mahārāj disse: «Mi dispiace,
but we are forbidden to enter into those subject matters.”
ma a noi è proibito l'accesso a quegli argomenti».
And then he gave a very extensive talk about the guidelines,
Poi fece un discorso molto lungo in merito ai criteri
given by Śrīla Saraswatī Ṭhākur in Gauḍīya Maṭh,
dati da Śrīla Saraswatī Ṭhākur nella Gauḍīya Maṭh,
on confidential subject matters.
su argomenti confidenziali.
So, I know that the person who’s asking the question,
Allora, so che la persona che fa la domanda,
they’re referring to something I said previously,
si riferiscono a qualcosa che dissi precedentemente,
and so I mentioned what Śrīla Guru Mahārāj said,
ed allora ho menzionato ciò che disse Śrīla Guru Mahārāj
and that’s it— it’s not something to discuss further
e basta, non è qualcosa di cui discutere ulteriormente
or to try and go into the details of.
o di cui provare ad entrare nei dettagli.
We’re not forbidden to know that madhura-rasa exists—
Non ci è vietato sapere che esiste il madhura-rasa,
the Divine pastimes of Kṛṣṇa and Rādhārāṇī, Vraja-gopīs …
i passatempi divini di Kṛṣṇa e Rādhārāṇī, delle Vraja-gopī…
It’s not that we’re forbidden to know those things.
non è che ci è vietato sapere quelle cose.
What is forbidden is to attempt to go into the details;
Ciò che è vietato è di provare a scendere nei dettagli;
detailed analysis, detailed explanation.
analisi dettagliate, spiegazioni dettagliate.
Because then, first of all it’s beyond our adhikār—
Perché allora, prima di tutto è oltre il nostro adhikār —
our capacity, our eligibility, our qualification—
le nostre capacità, i nostri requisiti, le nostre qualifiche —
and that ensures that aparādh, offence, will be committed along the way.
e ciò assicura che aparādh, le offese, saranno commesse lungo il cammino.
And when it comes to these things, this is the Supreme Reality.
Quando si tratta di queste cose, questa è la Suprema Realtà.
We don’t want to err.
Non vogliamo errare.